Gouri Bajpai

UX and UI Designer

Fremont. California

747-256-2121 | gouri.bajp@gmail.com LinkedIn | Portfolio

SUMMARY

UX researcher and designer with a background in commerce, fine art, and information technology. I strive to tackle design problems through the use of empathy and mindfulness. I bring a skill set of UX research, lo-fidelity wireframing to hi-fidelity prototyping using Figma. I am also familiar with HTML, CSS, and Java which helps me communicate with the development team. Passionate about developing intuitive, useful, human-centered designs. Interested in AR/VR.

SKILLS

Tools: Figma, Miro, Maze, Adobe XD, Photoshop, Sketch, Google Suite, Canva, Notion, Jira, Slack **Strengths**: Double Diamond Design Process, User-Centered Design

UX Design, Sketching, User Research: Qualitative, Quantitative, Card sorting, Competitive Analysis(SWOT), Personas, User Stories, User Flows, Sitemap, UI Design, Wireframes, Low-fidelity Prototyping, Branding, High-fidelity Prototyping, Usability Testing, Mock-ups, Teamwork.

PROJECTS

VS I Project Link

- Designed a mobile app which allows high schoolers to see the list of volunteer opportunities nearby.
- Users can directly communicate with people who seek help in an open room kind of setup.
 Not one on one chat for safety reasons.
- Designed hi-fidelity prototype in three weeks to reach MVP standards from start to finish
- Created with Figma, Miro and Maze

Flight Ez | Project Link

- Designed a mobile app which allows private pilots and student pilots to filter the aircrafts based on their specs. and book an aircraft conveniently.
- Designed a mid-fidelity prototype in three weeks to reach MVP standards.
- Created with Figma, Adobe XD, Miro and Maze

Bus King | Project Link

• Designed a mobile app that helps bus riders identify the buses arriving at a multi-line bus stop, view bus arrival

times, and view time required to travel to the bus stop.

- Contributed to every phase of the design process, as the sole designer, from discovery to delivery.
- Created with Figma and Miro.

EXPERIENCE

Creative Director & Lead Artist

Radiant Art Studios | Fremont, CA

- Lead paint nights for adults and teens.
- Taught depiction of storytelling, and encouraged visual analysis.
- Imparted creative problem solving and hand-eye coordination skills

Assistant UX Designer

May 2015 - Oct 2020

Fidypay | Indore, MP May 2017 – Jan 2020

• Translated concepts into personas, journey map, empathy map, user flows, user stories that lead to intuitive user experiences

• Facilitated qualitative research interviews.

EDUCATION

CERTIFICATE, UX/UI DESIGN

2020-2021

Thinkful/Bloc, Remote

Learned design thinking, design process and principles with a focus on User Centered Design and the Double Diamond Design Process.

Master Of Science (IT)

Expected graduation July 2021

Dr. C.V. Raman University, Remote

Master Of Arts 1999-2001

Dr. H.S.G VV

Bachelor of Commerce 1995-1998

Dr. H.S.G VV

Volunteer Work

Web Designer faculty member

Sep 2012 - May 2014

Fremont Unified School District

I took the initiative to start a Web Designing Program at Mattos Elementary school. It was designed especially for the Intermediate level. I could get the help of a few volunteers to make this program successful. The curriculum had HTML and CSS.

Boldly Me (Non-Profit Organisation)

Aug 2012 - Present

- I do participate in their FundRaising Events by donating my canvas oil paintings
- Donate my hours for temporary henna tattoo art and generate funds throughout the year.

Event Organizer Sep 2017 - Present

Thornton Junior High School

Historian

PTSA at Thornton Junior High School Oct 2020 - Present

Committee member

Boys Scout of America Troop 449 Nov 2018 - Present